# **EMILY PAGE**

Address . 43 Onslow Road, Rochester, Kent, ME1 2AL Phone. 07795041892

Email · <u>epageone81@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/emily-page-software/

Passionate teaching professional committed to providing students with positive educational experiences. Quickly builds productive relationships through excellent communication and instruction. Adapts teaching styles and methods to maximise student potential.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

- NOVEMBER 2023 PRESENT
- TEACHING ASSISTANT, KING'S SCHOOL ROCHESTER
- Oversaw one student on EHCP and with Medical Needs throughout his classes and working on one-to-one sessions.
- Delivered additional learning support opportunities to one student, enabling improved academic confidence.
- Maximised student engagement and receptive learning by educating students using individualised instructional approaches.
- Observed children when teacher needed a five-minute break out of class and encouraged positive choices for minimising and resolving conflicts.
- Recommended additional materials and resources to improve student skills.
- Taught student in one-to-one sessions important learning, study and behaviour management skills for academic success.
- Boosted academic achievement of special needs student through compassionate, considered individual tutoring.
- Monitored children in spaces between classes, keeping disruptions to minimum.
- Supervised students in wider school environments, offering reliable dining room, library and playground support.
- Developed and nurtured excellent relationships with students and staff, enhancing positive learning environments.
- Supported teachers in managing challenging student behaviour within the classroom.
- APRIL 2017 AUGUST 2023
- **MUSIC TECH TUTOR,** NOVUS
- Taught practical lessons in Music Technology to develop applied learning
- Directed students in completing assignments and projects related to subject material.
- Organised materials and spaces to support student learning and engagement for optimum learning.
- Created lessons to lay out foundational theories and concepts and ready students for advanced topics.
- Monitored and quickly implemented required curriculum changes.

- Logged student grades, attendance and participation in Mixcrat9/Cubase11 software.
- Supported students to reach curriculum goals with tailored coaching style.
- Issued detailed course outline information before commencement to inform students about topics of study.
- Tutored students in one-to-one and small group sessions to progress learning.
- Used established assessment criteria to evaluate student skills and knowledge gaps.
- Developed courses and resources for enhanced additional learning.
- Taught practical lessons in Music Technology to develop applied learning.
- Observed developments in teaching methods and technologies to innovate current practices.
- Logged student grades, attendance and participation in Mixcraft9/Cubase11 software.
- Analysed student progress and prepared feedback to improve coursework results.
- Utilised technology in tutoring sessions to diversify and enhance learning.
- Modelled respect for students' diverse cultures, language skills and experiences to create welcoming environment.
- Offered subject specialist information, advice and support to learners as part of teaching duties.
- Enforced appropriate behaviour when delivering sessions to minimise distractions.
- Helped curriculum manager in successful operational management of curriculum area.
- Proffered direct assistance in use of equipment, learning objects and materials needed for student success.
- Simplified complex theory through clear, relevant teachings.
- Employed listening and questioning strategies to diagnose student needs and monitor progress.
- Examined feedback and made necessary changes to improve practice.
- Used pre-determined resources to deliver tutoring as outlined in company policies.
- Kept and updated students' Individual Learning Plans and records to help evaluate progress and areas for development.
- Gave early intervention support to students beginning to struggle with materials.
- Adapted classes to meet requirements of special needs children.

#### • JUNE 2016 TO APRIL 2017

#### LEARNING SUPPORT PRACTITIONER, NOVUS

- I also worked on a rotational basis with my other colleagues within the Learning Support department on the Outreach Programme
- This consisted of working with young people that cannot attend the main education pathways due to behaviour or vulnerability within HMYOI Cookham Wood
- The main educational duties are literacy and numeracy work either on a one-to-one basis or within a small group such as two or three.
- Created and distributed instructional materials for group and one-on-one use to provide resources and materials, enhancing learning experience.
- Prepared visual aids, equipment and classroom displays to use for presentations and engaging lectures.
- Studied students in classroom setting to determine academic needs and struggling areas, providing extra attention and care.
- Utilised curriculum with life-based approach to share experiences and resonate with personal stories.

- Completed documentation to submit reports and brief management on student behaviours, interventions and results.
- Encouraged students to engage in peer interaction to establish and increase social skills.
- Researched industry trends to stay abreast with updated teaching practices.
- Maintained focused inclusive and supportive learning environments to avoid disruptions and optimise workflow.
- Liaised with team of professionals to implement comprehensive educational action plans for special needs and at-risk students.
- Enforced classroom rules to instil discipline and avoid unruly behaviour.
- Undertook evaluations to measure performance and progress of students, providing direction and guidance to improve outcomes.

#### **OCTOBER 2008 - MAY 2016**

#### NIGHT TIME TRAINING CENTRE ASSISTANT, REBOUND

- Provided personal coaching for clients requiring one-on-one support, teaching strength and endurance techniques.
- Closely monitored and supervised customers to properly use equipment, promptly intervening to avoid safety risks.
- Carried out security surveillance activities in lockers, changing rooms and other facilities, keeping areas free from theft or security breaches.
- Maintained ongoing presence in circulation spectator and ancillary areas to provide accessibility and assistance to guests.
- Attended regular first aid and CPR training to keep updated on emergency procedures and best practices.
- Recorded and reported injuries or accidents for security to identify causes and avoid future risks, following safety protocols.
- Aided management in implementing and revising policies and procedures to maintain peace and order and compliance from guests.
- Conducted in-depth quality inspections on equipment before and after use, determining equipment retain functionality and performance.
- Reported disruptive and unruly behaviour to security to instil discipline and compliance with facility rules and regulations.
- Stored, secured and recorded deliveries, replenishing stock to maintain complete supply and consistent inventory.
- Examined safety conditions to determine emergency action plan, minimising security risks.
- Followed sanitation and hygiene guidelines by carrying out regular housekeeping tasks to eliminate waste and reduce contaminants.
- Independently managed emergencies following procedures and applying first aid to respond and address situation, avoiding severe cases.

#### **EDUCATION**

**OCTOBER 2023 TO MAY 2005** 

## BA (HONS) CREATIVE MUSIC PRODUCTION, UNIVERSITY OF KENT AT

#### **CANTERBURY**

My degree consisted of learning how to record audio and work with bands to record in a studio. Produce and mix down the audio work and create my own compositions using Digital Audio Workstations. I also learnt how parts of the Music Industry works such as publishing, copyright and the UK law in the industry

- Coursework in composition and producing audio.
- Dissertation in copyright and creativity.

#### OCTOBER 2001 TO JUNE 2003

# **HIGHER NATIONAL DIPLOMA IN MUSIC PRODUCTION,** UNIVERSITY OF KENT AT CANTERBURY.

My HND consisted of learning how to compose using Digital Audio Workstations, analyse music, and work on different genres and styles. Working as part of a group in recording sessions, mixing, and producing tracks.

## **SKILLS**

- Working with young people from all occupations and backgrounds.
- Plan and create lessons and activities that engage learners.
- Review and give constructive feedback.
- ICT skills using Word, Excel and PowerPoint
- Confidence building
- Friendly and personable
- Activity-based learning
- Concept explanations
- Adaptable nature
- Holistic teaching method
- Writing assessments
- Creative strategies
- Innovative lesson planning
- Individualised instruction
- Group instruction
- Personalised learning plans
- Interactive teaching/learning
- Curriculum development

#### **ACHIEVMENTS**

I have also achieved my DET – Level 5 Diploma in Teaching and my TAQA – Level 3 Assessor Qualification. I play in a band and my main instrument is the flute. I have played for charity concerts for Alzheimer's Society overtime as well as other gigs for the passion of playing live music.